coach said he wanted you guys to be
loose and focus and you are a lot more
than loose and focus. How would you
describe your defense tonight?
>> Man, it was it's insane, man. I've never
been around a bunch of guys that it's
literally nobody thought it was a Super
Bowl. It was literally just our next
game and that's how we approached it.
And defensively, we came out and we said
it early in the year to win the Super
Bowl is going to be on our back. So,
like I said ear, I'd be damned if we get
one game away and this defense don't
show up like we're supposed to.
>> No surprise.
>> You dominated the offensive line.
>> How do you think when you thought you
were able to do that so many times?
>> Yeah. I mean, you know, you you watch
the film. I I think you can you can get
misconstrued a lot of times. What you
see on film is truly what a team is. But
I think with us, man, once we get in
front of you, we're a different group.
So we were able to get out there, get
pressure, and you know, get after the
quarterback.
>> The dark side defense had to win today
in history.
>> How does it feel to live up to the
>> man? It feels it's what what I imagined,
what I expected from us. Um, we've been
doing this all year. We've been battle
tested. This this this was nothing.
>> Ernest,
>> I'm go here and then I'll come right to
you.
>> Thank you. Hi, Ernest.
What has it been like to see Sam Darnold
revive his career across the country
with you guys and and just way he's led
that offense?
>> Um it's it's a unique story, man. I'm
I'm I'm super blessed that that guy is
my quarterback. I think he just models
what everybody in that team's been
through. Man, we've all been rejected.
We've all um not been respected. And
he's just a guy at the helm for us. And
he's a hell of a player. and I'm super
thankful he's my quarterback,
>> man. Honestly, said all said and done,
boy, there's a bunch of bad boys and for
me to be in the middle of that to be the
leader of that group, I'm blessed. Um I
I told I told everybody, man, the
saddest part about this week, honestly,
was that we won't it won't be the same
group. That's that's honestly the
saddest part about this thing is, you
know, everybody's not going to be able
to be back and but we know what it takes
to play football and play defense for a
Seattle defense. So, we'll carry that
on.
>> Man, it's been rough, man. I think this
this this didn't start this year. It
started last year. We couldn't stop the
run for nothing to save, you know, save
our lives early on. Then I came, then we
were able to make some changes, but I
noticed then we were getting better. We
were a team that if you had let us in
the playoffs last year, we we were going
to cause damage, too. Um, but I knew
coming into this year, we we were
special. We just had to go do it.
>> I'm go here and then I'm going go right
to you.
>> Oh, and then you I'm sorry about that.
I'm sorry.
defense compared to some of the other
would
>> I think that's for y'all. I mean, you
could say certain things and you know,
they played way less games back then.
Um, I will say this, my defense, I match
us up against anybody. I like us versus
any and whoever. Um, so whatever offense
you throw out there, whatever great
offense you can put together, I like us.
I like our odds.
>> How does it feel to be a major
contributor for two Super Bowls? I mean,
Rams and
>> it's amazing, man. Two time. Never
thought I'd be saying that I'd be a
twotime world champion.
Brought the first one here. I can't I
said earlier in the year I wanted a twin
and I knew this was a team for it. Were
there any
small
things that you guys did today?
>> No, we've been we've been running those
all year. They just they just hit today.
Um I think with the way that they're
schematically they were thinking what
you know what we were going to do. those
nickel pressures came available and they
were open. And honestly, Spoon's been
open on a lot of those blitzes, but
sometimes I don't do my job and go
underneath the running back, so it'll
mess him up sometimes.
>> I think everybody has to do
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think everybody has to do
their job. you know, certain players
have to get out of the way so that Spoon
can, you know, get get in those gaps,
but also I think, you know, pre- snap,
showing pressure away from those snaps,
getting the quarterback looking the
other way, and then boom, it's right on
him. So, I think that's what it was.
>> How would you describe how Witherspoon
is, how valuable he is to your
>> He's a dog. I I said it. He's my
favorite player in the NFL, man. He can
do everything. Go play outside, inside.
>> Man, he's a walk-in Hall of Famer right
now.
What distinguishes
>> I'm come to you.
>> You go ahead and go ahead.
>> What distinguishes your defense from
other Why are you guys so effective?
>> I think we really don't care the
situation. We don't care about how many
yards you got to play before every play.
We feel like every play that you run is
opportunity as far as to take the ball
away. And I've never been around a group
of guys who believe that defense win
championships. I've never been around a
group of guys that take pride in playing
defense and these guys do that.
>> I'm gonna come to you right now. Go
ahead.
>> That was uh that was everything, man. We
we we wouldn't have been successful
against this team. If we first didn't
rush and, you know, make it hard for
Drake, but if we didn't cover on the
back end, too, they got really electric
receivers, tight ends. So we game plan
was tight from what Mike and AD had and
we went and executed.
Yeah, my mindset was just, man,
>> keep these guys going. Um, there was no
need for me to get two up or two down,
man. I I'm that constant leader in the
middle, so I got to be just that
regardless of the situation, regardless
of the game. I mean, what we've seen
from them is what we've been seeing on
film. You know, we just thought that we
were just defensively we could just just
do what we needed to to do to win this
game. And I'm glad guys just came out
and just did just that.
the NFC.
>> I mean, I've always said it that the NFC
NFC West. I mean, when those when the
NFC's rolling, I truly believe the best
teams come out of there.
>> Feels like between the ring and the
cigar, you've been enjoying this. I
>> mean, I've been enjoying this,
>> man. everybody.
I don't want to say we expected this cuz
we were never cocky, but we were
we were we were committed. This year was
a failure if we didn't get to this point
and win the game. Um we knew what type
of team we were early on, day in and day
out. We just had to do it. And I commend
these men because nobody works harder
than us in the league and we did it day
in and day out.
difference
looks in order to make things diff.
>> Yeah, we definitely had to switch it up.
I mean, he he he's to be in year two.
The man's smart. He can make all the
throws. We had to switch it up, keep him
guessing, but early on, you know, this
big stage,
you got to get after him. And I think
that was our game plan early on. We told
the Dline like, "Y'all got to go win us
this game." And they did just that.
>> Didn't seem like you've seen a lot of
pressure this year. And you had
obviously a couple safety blitz to get
to him. Did you guys see that on tape?
And is that part of what you were
thinking?
>> Magician Mike. Man, Mike Mike,
you know, he he saved stuff for certain
weeks and I think he, you know, dialed
those up because he know that that would
just, you know, help us be successful.
But Mike and AD came up with those, you
know, blitzes and we just go execute.
>> I'mma come right to you after.
I mean, I was young. I think I I enjoyed
it a lot more. I I didn't
Let me take that back. I I was young. I
didn't appreciate it the first time as
much as I should have. And I'm blessed
that God gave me another chance to
really appreciate it. Um, so I think
that's the difference for me from the
first and second time. a lot older. I
understand that it takes everything to
get to this point.
>> Amen. All glory to God. Thank you.
>> Man, they mean everything to us. Like
Mike spoke about it, you know, before
this game. He's like, man, we he
a two down linebacker. I wanted to to to
play all the downs and to
developing that skill set to to be out
there on the field all the time. That's
what I want. I I don't want to come off
the field and you know, I'm the mic for
a reason. So, you don't take your leader
out of battle. So, that's how I feel
about it.
>> Right.
It's a
>> it's a mindset, you know, that we're
coming in there and we're going to try
to stop the run with two safeties. It's
up to you to do something different and
the our mindset is you don't run the
ball and we we make it tough for you to
throw the ball and you know, we see what
happens at the end of the game.
>> One of the best tough corners in the
NFL. He blitzes 10 times, makes a huge.
What's that versatility mean?
>> He's everything, bro. Like, that man is
amazing. He But but you don't see the
work he puts in to be that player day in
and day out. He puts in the work and I
mean, he's great. Like I said, he's
walking home hall of fame. What is this?
Is his third year, three Pro Bowls. He's
a Super Bowl champion now. Like, what
what what are we doing?
>> I'm come right to you.
>> Kickers don't always get the credit. win
this game without Jason Myers going
five. What does that mean?
>> J is the man. Like when he goes out
there to take a kick, I think everybody
on our team lets out a side because he's
he's just automatic. We believe and we
trust him. And Jay's the man.
>> Thank you.
>> Where have I grown? I've grown in so
many places. Um,
>> I think for me, I'm a I'm naturally like
when it's time to go to war, I go. Um,
but I've been able to these guys have
taught me to calm down. They these guys
are teaching me the the emotion in the
ocean, just staying calm, man. And and
they've helped me. They keep me
grounded. So, I think that's been the
biggest thing is when things aren't
going our way or when they are, staying
just that constant leader.
his life on the sideline defensive
sideline when maybe after the first
quarter after the first few weeks drives
like it's pretty clear you guys are
dominating like what's that emotion like
with your guys with yourself personally
that you feel like you're dominating
this game
>> I think the mo the emotion is
>> we all felt it we felt it during the
game that we were dominating even when
they scored the touchdown they scored
because that was a a lack of us looking
ahead um I think
I think for I think for us I I think we
just it takes a lot to lock in on those
really moments where you got them where
you got them on the ropes and you know
you have them. But I but I think that's
where you know Mike's came in where
Mike's been really like no matter what
the way anything's going he keeps us
straight ahead going forward. So I think
that's what was able to help us today.
>> Thank you.
>> I'mma go here and then
I'd also I'd recommend hard work, but I
I think the biggest thing that I could
recommend, man, Jesus Christ, what's for
you is for you. Um, in it and in Jesus
Christ, there's a lot of hope, man. Find
Jesus, find God, build a relationship
with him, and, you know, see what
happens. See where life takes you.
In college, what helped me the most,
man, I I just lost him a couple months
ago, but my dad, you know, being able to
speak to my dad about life when things
were rough, that meant everything to me.
So, my dad and just, you know, any
mentor that you can have, that's a great
positive role model. I think those are
those are big.
Yeah, I think anytime you get pressure
on these quarterbacks, you don't allow
them to sit back there and, you know,
count sheep. I mean, they it allows for
success. I think that's what it was for
us. Man, the man is the man is going to
be a heck of a quarterback. Um, but I
think for us, we had to go out there and
we knew how important he was to that
offense, so we had to take him away. We
had to get after him and you know we
were able to do so.
>> I'll do one more.
>> It feels amazing. Second ring. Uh it
it's hit me a little bit but I'm so
excited for this parade. I cannot wait.
>> Thank you.